Umair Shahid

Java Developer

CONTACT



Rawalpindi, Pakistan



umairshahid.pn@gmail.com



(+92) 315 5543298



https://www.linkedin.com/in/umair-s88

live:umairshahid 3 (Skype)

SKILLS

- Java
- JSF / Primefaces
- Hibernate
- **Spring Boot**
- Spring Data
 Spring Security
 Spring Cloud
- SQL (MySQL)
- NoSQL (MongoDB)
- GitLab
- Bitbucket
- Jira
- RabbitMQ

LANGUAGES

Proficient English Native Urdu

DIPLOMA

2011 - Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Diploma in Information Technology

Punjab Board of Technical Education

ABOUT ME

Experienced, motivated and skill full software engineer with a strong ability to determine projects, operational feasibility and design. I am having 3+ years of experience in backend and right now I am working in Royal Cyber Inc. as a Java developer. My tasks are to develop web services. I have a strong background in team management tools such as Jira, GitLab, Bitbucket. Experienced in Analysis, Design, Development, Testing and Deployment of applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE



Java Developer

Royal Cyber

- · Worked with project managers to design and implement scalable solution
- Worked in a team-based environment
- Development of Rest APIs using Spring Boot
- Integration of Middleware
- Ecommerce development using HCL commerce
- · Design, Create and Maintain Database

JUL 2020 - DEC 2021 - Islamabad, Pakistan

Associate Software Engineer

Evamp and Saanga

- Analyzed requirements
- Developing Rest APIs using Jboss Fuse and Spring Boot
- Integration of Middleware
- Design, Create and Maintain Database
- Deployment support

JUN 2019 - JUL 2020 - Islamabad, Pakistan

Junior Software Engineer

Business Analytics

- Developing web applications using JSF (Java Server Faces)
- Developing Rest APIs using Java and Spring Boot
- Design, Create and Maintain Database for web and mobile applications

EDUCATION

2014 –2018 – Rawalpindi, Pakistan

BS Software Engineering

Virtual University of Pakistan

DEC 2021 - Ongoing

YOC (Your Own Commerce)

It is an e-commerce product which use Magento, HCl commerce, and commerce tools in its background to give freedom to companies to switch between these platforms, and built their own ecommerce platform

My role is to consume HCL commerce API related to product and cart and develop middleware Rest APIs for front end

Tools & Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Security, MySQL DB, Jira,

JAN 2021 - DEC 2021

Salam DMS

It is a mobile app of Saudi telecom company Salam for agents where they can assign and issue sim cards, activate sim cards, apply packages, and all other sim card related activities.

Backend development of Salam (Saudi telecom company) mobile app

Tools & Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring Cloud, Maria DB, Jira, GitLab

JUL 2020 - DEC 2021

Jazz Business World

It is B2B web portal where users are able to track their transactions, apply packages, transfer mobile funds, create line numbers if user is POC, track its line number and their transaction.

Back-end development of Jazz (Pakistan's Telecom network) business portal

Tools & Technologies: Java, Jboss fuse, Apache Camel, My SQL, ActiveMQ

AUG 2020 - DEC 2020

Maroctel Payment Reconciliation

It is B2B web portal where users are able to track their transactions, apply packages, transfer mobile funds, create line numbers if user is POC, track its line number and their transaction.

Back-end development of Jazz (Pakistan's Telecom network) business portal

Tools & Technologies: Spring Boot, My SQL, GitLab

JAN 2020 - JUL 2020

GRAP (Online grocery store)

Online grocery application, which provide user to purchase products, place orders. It is an inhouse product of company which is used to sell their own products.

REST web services for online grocery store. Sales, customers, products and orders record keeping (POS)

Tools & Technologies: Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA, MySQL

JUN 2019 - JUL 2020

Farms Management System

It is a management application in which users (Farm owners) can add records related to their and animals and products and then check their productivity levels, track profit margins and analyze farm growth. This portal also keeps records of employees and contract workers.

Record Keeping, Basic accountancy, sale and production analysis of dairy farms and crops

Tools & Technologies: JSF, MySQL, Hibernate, Git